Finding Aid for International Reform Federation records, 1893-1949
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
International Reform Federation records 1893-1949
International Reform Federation.
5 microfilm reels and 0.5 linear feet
851511 Bj microcopy; Bj 2
Social reform organization within the Methodist Church concerned with the promotion of temperance and peace founded by Wilbur F. Crafts. Cashbooks, correspondence, minutes of annual meetings, appointment books and newspaper clippings.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records came from the organization (donor no. 4937 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The International Reform Federation was a social reform organization within the Methodist Church concerned with the promotion of temperance and peace. The organization was founded by Wilbur F. Crafts.
The record group consists of cashbooks and a financial ledger (on microfilm) and a scattering of original materials, including correspondence, minutes of annual meetings, appointment books and newspaper clippings.
Subjects:
Methodist Church (U.S.); Peace--Societies, etc.; Social reformers--United States.; Temperance--United States.; International Reform Federation, inc.; Crafts, Wilbur F. (Wilbur Fisk). 1850-1922.
- Cashbooks, 1911-1921
  - March 1911-May 1912 (Reel 1)
  - May 1912-May 1913 (Reel 1)
  - May 1913-February 1914 (Reel 1)
  - February-December 1914 (Reel 2)
  - December 1914-October 1915 (Reel 2)
  - November-1915-June 1916, This volume was not received. (Reel 2)
  - July 1916-March 1917 (Reel 2)
  - March 1917-January 1918 (Reel 2)
  - February 1918-November 1919, This volume was not received. (Reel 2)
  - December 1919-November 1920 (Reel 2)
  - December 1920-November 1921 (Reel 2)
  - November 1921-December 1922 (Reel 3)
  - December 1922-January 1924 (Reel 3)
  - January 1924-April 1925 (Reel 3)
  - May 1925-December 1926 (Reel 3)
  - December 1926-September 1928 (Reel 3)
  - October 1928-July 1930 (through July 1929) (Reel 3)
  - October 1928-July 1930 (begins August 1929) (Reel 4)
  - July 1930-June 1932 (Reel 4)
  - July 1932-November 1934 (Reel 4)
  - December 1934-October 1936 (Reel 4)
  - November 1936-December 1938 (Reel 4)
  - December 1916-August 1921 (scattered dates) (Reel 5)
- Other records, 1911-
  - Ledger, 1911-1913 (Reel 5)
  - Correspondence, 1927-1940
  - Minutes of annual meetings, 1928-1949 (Box 1)
    - 1928-1936 (Box 1)
    - 1937-1949 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1893-1905 and undated (Box 1)
  - Papers regarding the case of Schmidt vs. Chase, et al., 1935-1936 (Box 1)
  - Office diary, 1915 (fragmentary) (Box 1)
  - Office diary, 1934 (fragmentary) (Box 1)